## Florent Cuer

# Software Developer Laravel - ReactJS

**Bristol, UK** 

Contact



+44 7472 533849



florentcuer+jobs@gmail.com



Github FloCRC



in LinkedIn florent-cuer





Portfolio Website

#### **Skills**

Laravel **PHP** 

ReactJS **JavaScript** 

HTML

CSS

**MySQL** 

### **Hobbies**

**Badminton** Hiking

Camping

**Board Games** 

**Computer Games** 

Right to Work **Settled Status** 

Full-Stack Software Developer - Laravel, PHP, ReactJS

I'm making a career change into software development as I enjoy coding and get a lot of satisfaction out of problem solving. I've grown up on computers, building computers, and being the go-to person in work and with family for tech. Outside of work I enjoy hiking, camping, and playing board games.

## iO Academy Bootcamp - May 2024 - August 2024

I recently studied software development at iO Academy where I worked on both front-end and back-end projects, individually and as part of a scrum team. These can be seen in my portfolio. Below are two of my key projects.

## React - Invoicing Web App

The purpose of this project was to build a web app to be able to manage invoices. This was a group project built with JavaScript, HTML and Tailwind CSS, using the ReactJS library. ReactJS was used as it made groupwork easier to manage with its component structure, which made merging different sections smoother.





Github Live Demo

## Laravel - Bookswap API

The purpose of this project was to build a **RESTful API** for an existing front-end project. This was a group project built with PHP, using object oriented programming and the Laravel framework. Laravel helped us structure the use of the MVC design pattern to interact with our database.





Github Documentation 🛱 API 🔼 Live Demo



## **Job History**

## Bathroom Showroom Manager / BBS Plumbing & Heating Supplies Ltd

February 2022 - April 2024, Bristol, UK

In this role I designed and sold bathrooms, as well as managed projects between end user and installer. I managed two staff members directly in my showroom, and headed up a team of 6 employees across three showrooms. I was in charge of training new staff. I managed team operations including regular team meetings to manage workloads and upcoming enquiries.

### Bathroom Showroom Consultant / BBS Plumbing & Heating Supplies Ltd

November 2019 - February 2022, Bristol, UK

### CAD Draughtsman / Realserve Pty Ltd

August 2018 - September 2019, Auckland, New Zealand

#### Career Break / Travel

August 2017 - August 2018

## **ESL Teacher /** Sapporo City Board of Education

August 2012 - August 2017, Sapporo, Japan

#### **Education**

## Bachelor of Design - Major in Interior Architecture /

Victoria University of Wellington

February 2008 - October 2011, Wellington, New Zealand

NCEA Level 3 (A Level Equivalent in New Zealand)

Maths with Calculus, Physics, Chemistry, English, Art Design